预约你九点接人的吗
Book you for 9:00?
今天你可以休息了
Take the day off.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
All right.
你犯了什么事
So what did you do?
你知道我在监狱里
You figured out I was in jail,
却不知何故吗
but you don't know why?
我最近很忙
I've been busy.
滥开处方
Excessive prescribing.
也没忙到那么好忽悠
Not that busy.
我知道你最终得到滥开处方的轻判
I know that you pled down to excessive prescribing,
问题是  你到底做了什么
but the question was "What did you do?"
36岁  不吸烟的初中科学教师
36-year-old, non-smoking junior high science teacher
在早点名时开始咳血
started coughing blood in the middle of homeroom.
豪斯说他要在外逍遥三天
House says he's gonna be out for the next three days.
太好了  如果我现在赶去机场
Sweet. If I go straight to the airport,
刚好能赶上前往卡波的飞机
I can make Cabo for the last call.
他还说如果我们找到病例就给他打电话
He also said to call him if we find a case.
-我们没能找到  -那这怎么说
- Which we didn't. - What do you call this?
可以是  也可以什么都不是
Could be a case. Could be nothing.
非常遗憾  我们不打算探其究竟
Sadly, we'll just never know.
他在咳血
He's coughing blood.
很多人都咳血
A lot of people are.
我得马上赶到弗农市去
Right now I have to get to Vernon
趁着还有雪可以滑
while there's still enough powder to ski on.
此刻  小人就会拿黑人滑雪开涮
This is where a lesser man would make a black-guy-skiing joke.
说快点  我正开车呢
Make it fast. I'm driving.
我可不想进监狱  就像
I don't want to end up in jail like...
开车时违章打电话的人活该进监狱那样
a person should who used their phone illegally while driving.
36岁  男性  症状包括咳血
36-year-old male with hemoptysis,
头痛  寒战和胸痛
headaches, chills, and chest pain.
你人在哪里
Where are you?
我正开车去参加大斯克内克塔迪县的
On my way to the Greater Schenectady
辣豆汤烹饪和土豆大炮比赛
Chili Cook- Off and Spud Gun Competition.
这是你们的蜜月旅行吗
That's your honeymoon?
不  多米尼卡跟她男友去亚特兰大城了
Nope, Dominika went to A.C. with her boyfriend.
急诊室已经排除了支气管炎
E.R. ruled out bronchitis,
肺炎和肺癌的诊断
pneumonia, and lung cancer.
真无聊  那就是鼻衄
So diagnosis--boring. It's epistaxis.
不过是流鼻血嘛
It's a nosebleed.
血液流进肺部  咳嗽时被带了出来
Blood runs into his lungs, he coughs it back up,
流感可以解释其它症状
flu explains the rest of the symptoms.
流鼻血第一次  流鼻血第二次
Going once, going twice...
氨气或亚硫酸盐中毒
Toxic exposure to ammonia or sulfites
可能损伤肺脏
can traumatize the lungs,
引起神经痛或发烧
cause neuralgias or fevers.
他有放射性胸痛  更符合中毒的诊断
Fits better because of his radiating chest pain.
成交  马斯特斯中标
Sold. To Masters.
去他家寻找毒素来源
Do a home search for toxins.
抽血做细菌和真菌培养
Draw cultures for bacteria and fungi.
你结婚了
You're married?
你离开我们太久了
You were gone so long.
为了绿卡
Green card.
谢谢你替我保密
Thanks for not saying anything.
我需要一些时间
I just need some time to...
这可不是为了你
I didn't do it for you.
是我舍不得将你的入狱之谜与人分享
Some puzzles are just too good to share.
就是这个出口
This is my exit.
辣豆汤  没搞错吧
Chili?
我讨厌辣豆汤  喜欢土豆大炮
I hate chili. Love spud guns.
你之前出过鼻血吗
You get nosebleeds?
对  出过
Yeah, yeah.
你觉得咳出来的是鼻血吗
You think that's where the blood came from?
不只是觉得  我希望它就是
I don't just think it. I hope it.
上一次流鼻血是什么时候
When was the last time it happened?
四分之一决赛的时候
At the quarterfinals.
我是排球教练  几个月之前
I coach volleyball, and during warm-ups
赛前热身的时候我被球砸到了鼻子
I got hit in the nose a few months ago.
你是在体育馆里当教练吗
You coach volleyball in a gym?
是的
Yes.
-有浴室的那种吗  -对
- With showers? -Yes.
-浴室干净吗  -不是特别干净
- Clean showers? - Not particularly.
你咳出来的似血而非血
The blood you were coughing up wasn't blood.
脏兮兮的体育馆浴室意味着沙雷氏菌感染
Dirty gym washroom means serratia infection.
你的肺里充满了红色的细菌
Your lungs are full of red bacteria.
你说得对  这还真是个有意思的病例
You were right. That was an interesting case.
开始给他用左氧氟沙星
You start him on levaquin.
我去找我那双舒服的人字拖了
I'll start looking for my good flip-flops.
我觉得那好像是血
Think that might be blood.
豪斯  你到底为什么要参加这个比赛
What's this really all about, House?
我不太相信你对蔬菜炮弹
As convincing as I find your deep devotion
痴迷到这种程度
to vegetable trajectory.
首先  土豆是植物的块茎
First of all, it's a tuber.
其次  你和土豆的交集顶多是上薯条
And you're just jealous because your potato-related plans
所以你有点嫉妒
are more of the serving up fries variety.
你进了监狱
You did time.
说明你的行医执照被暂时吊销
Means your license is suspended,
这也说明你的假期
which means your leave of absence
一定会被无限期的延长
is definitely indefinite.
你这么着急回去干什么呢
What exactly are you going back to?
就算卖薯条我也只需要卖到
I'd only have to serve up fries
召开医委会听证会之时
until the medical board hearing.
我认错
I stand corrected.
显然丰富多彩的生活正等着你回来
You obviously have a rich, full life waiting for you.
我会减速  你自觉下车吧
I'll slow down the car and you can roll out.
我都还没换身衣服呢
I don't even have a change of clothes.
真糟糕  我之前怎么没想到呢
Damn. If only I'd planned for that.
好吧  我是这样猜想的
Okay, here's what I got.
第一  你在监狱里呆了六个月
One, you were in jail for six months,
但消失了近一年
but you were gone about a year,
也就是说你离开的时候还没被逮捕
which means that when you left you hadn't been arrested.
第二  你喜欢被人以数字称呼
Two, you enjoy being known as a number.
不想让别人了解你的真实面貌
You don't want people to know the real you,
因为你觉得真实的你很软弱
because you think the real you is weak.
你应该是在经营
You were running...
老好人医疗咨询业务
a bleeding-heart medical consulting business
专为非法移民
for illegals,
或别的可怜兮兮的底层人民服务
or some other sympathetic under-class.
不是
No.
那是超富阶层
Over-class?
你的审问越来越烦人了
This interrogation thing is getting annoying.
研究表明  不烦人的审问效率
Studies have shown that un-annoying interrogation
要差一半呢
is 50% less effective.
你为什么非拉我去参加这比赛呢
Why are you so determined to bring me to this competition?
为什么不带威尔森
Why don't you bring Wilson?
威尔森觉得这比赛很蠢
Wilson thinks it's stupid.
我也这么觉得
I think it's stupid.
你上初中时
Junior year of high school,
在西弗吉尼亚州际科学竞赛中得了第四
you placed fourth in a West Virginia All-County Science Fair.
项目是清洁燃烧
Your project, clean combustion.
是  我当时还戴少女文胸呢
Yeah, I also wore a training bra.
物是人非
Things have changed.
其实没变多少
Not that much.
我已经连续四年参加这个比赛了
I've been going to this contest for four years.
四年来我一直屈居亚军
For four years I've come second
全败在一个叫哈罗德·兰姆的小毛孩手里
to a pissant named Harold Lam.
你较真了
This is serious?
千年老二啊
Second.
好吧
Okay.
我可以帮你
I can help you,
但我中途要下车做个私人拜访
But I'm going to need to make a personal stop along the way.
什么拜访
What kind of stop?
私人拜访
Personal.
不是说过了吗
Did I not mention that?
你打算告诉我你昨夜的行程吗
You gonna tell me where you were last night?
碰巧遇见个朋友
I ran into a friend.
咱们在公牛队身上押了五十块钱呢
We had 50 bucks on the Bulls.
我还得独自消灭一大份比萨
I had to eat a large pizza by myself.
你想我啦
You missed me.
更想我那五十块钱
Not as much as I miss my $50.
你在哪碰到她的
Where'd you meet her?
医院里
At the hospital.
如果是马斯特斯  你直接骗我得了
If it's Masters, just lie to me.
是三楼新来的那个执业护工
Oh. It's the new CNA on the third floor.
那个红头发的  有够辣哦
The redhead. She's hot.
而且我们明晚还有约
And I'm seeing her again tomorrow night.
我真不知道你是怎么搞定的
I don't know how you do it.
是因为你可爱又人畜无害的气场
Is it the cute, harmless vibe,
还是自嘲的幽默  或者直接上迷药
the self-deprecating humor, or just straight-up roofies?
如果你有兴趣
If you're interested,
我可以授你几招
I do seminars.
没电  也没有煤气
No electric, no gas either.
屋里真冷
It's cold in here.
好消息是  我发现了一位
The good thing is I found a guy
比你还糟糕的室友
who makes you look like a good roommate.
也许囤积癖也是一种症状
Maybe hoarding's a symptom.
可能是由脑损伤引起的
Could be caused by brain injury
或是早发性老年痴呆
Or early-onset Alzheimer's.
多半应该还是心理问题
It's most likely that it's psychological.
至于他为什么会咳血
As to what's making him cough blood,
纯属自作自受
dealer's choice.
《整理你的家》  《贮藏家手册》
Declutter your home. The hoarder's handbook.
他把教人囤物的书也一起囤了
He's hoarding books on hoarding.
没有自来水
He doesn't have running water.
这家伙是怎么活下来的
How does this guy live,
更别说每天照常生活上班教学生了
let alone make it to work every day and teach a bunch of kids?
冰箱通着电  是从邻居或其它地方拉的线
Fridge is on. He's hooked it up to a neighbor or something.
一只死猫
Cat.
我快要吐了
I might have to throw up.
你的呕吐物他也会照单全收
He'll want to keep that too.
曲霉菌病
Aspergillosis.
可以解释咳血
Explains the coughing blood,
而且如果已形成了曲霉菌球
and if he's formed small aspergillomas,
也能解释头痛以及胸痛
it could explain the headache and chest pain.
我先回车里去
I'll be in the car.
好  右转
Okay, turn right.
你为了医用大麻开假处方
You were writing bogus prescriptions for medical marijuana.
快告诉我不是这样  这都能搞砸
Please say no because you have to be an idiot
那也太白痴了
to actually screw that up.
确实不是
No.
我是说  我这么干过  但没被逮到
I mean, I was, but I didn't get caught.
我得承认  在猜谜游戏里你的面部表情
I have to admit, you have one of the best game faces
叫人琢磨不透
I've ever seen.
肢体语言也是  有意思
Also one of the best game bodies.
停车
Pull over.
等着
Hang on a second.
看不出你还是耶和华见证会会员
Didn't know you were a Jehovah's witness.
是啊  耶稣没能在75年重新现世
Yeah, the weak lost faith
意志薄弱者便失去了信仰
when Christ didn't return in '75,
但我没有
but I still believe.
你真不打算告诉我刚刚是怎么回事吗
You're really not gonna tell me what just happened?
不知道你怎么样  我可是快饿死了
I don't know about you, but I am starving.
你们擅闯了我家
You broke into my home?
我们是慢慢推门而入的
We slowly pushed into your home.
找到什么了吗
So what did you find?
你冰箱里有一堆发臭的食物
A compost heap in your fridge.
我们觉得你得了曲霉菌病
We think you have aspergillosis.
可以用抗真菌药治疗
It's treatable with antifungals.
生活在你那种环境下
You do remarkably well for living...
这样已经很不错了
like you live.
我喝瓶装水  用手电筒
I use bottled water and flashlights.
就跟露营一样
It's like camping.
有意思
Fun.
我们还需要精神科医生会诊
We're also gonna need a psych consult.
我不是囤积病患者
I'm not a hoarder.
我只是比较懒
I'm just a major slob.
你连耳垢都存着
You save earwax.
你居然不知道我干了什么
You know, I'm actually kind of hurt
真让我感觉有点受伤
that you don't know what I did.
我不值得你贿赂法院工作人员
I'm not worth bribing a court official
或是黑进警局档案吗
or hacking into police records?
那有什么好玩的
Where's the fun in that?
你至少可以雇卡迪诡异的男朋友帮你
You could have at least hired Cuddy's weird boyfriend.
-卢卡斯  -没错
- Lucas? - Mm-hmm.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
什么  他是死了还是怎么样
What, is he dead or something?
不是
No.
实际上  直到几周以前
Actually, until a couple of weeks ago,
我就是卡迪诡异的男朋友
I was Cuddy's weird boyfriend.
下次你得编得再好点才行
You're gonna have to do a lot better than that.
你  你还好吗
Are--are you okay?
没事  还好
Yeah, I'm fine.
没什么大不了的
It's not a big deal.
我杀了个人
I killed a man.
精神评估没有任何问题
Psych eval gave us nothing.
那我们这病人就只是个
So our patient is just an average joe
收集了一堆半米多高用过的棉签的普通人
with a two-foot pile of used q-tips?
不管他是什么  反正他没患曲霉病
Whatever he is, he doesn't have aspergillosis.
痛感加强了  他现在还需要输氧
Pain's intensified, and now he needs oxygen.
那地方可能有各种各样的毒素
There's got to be all kinds of toxins in that place.
毒物暴露的说法说不通
Exposure issues don't make sense.
他在这一整天了
He's been here a full day.
情况应该好转的但反而恶化了
He'd be getting better, not worse.
除非接触到的毒物还在影响他
Unless exposure was keeping him from getting worse.
他住的地方没有煤气
The gas was off at his place.
-他怎么取暖  -便携式暖炉
- How does he stay warm? - Portable heater?
或者是便携式煤气炉
Or portable gas heater,
那会产生一氧化碳
which emits carbon monoxide.
从而导致血管舒张
Which is a vasodilator.
暴露在低浓度的一氧化碳中实际上
The low-grade exposure was actually improving
增加了他的肺活量
his lung capacity.
我们把他带到这来  他的情况就恶化了
We bring him here, he gets worse.
如果我们是对的  就不需要豪斯了
If we're right, don't need House,
并且还能放两天假
and we still get two days off.
我们还是得证明这点
We still have to prove it.
有人得回到他的住所检查一氧化碳浓度
Someone's got to go back into that place and test for C.O.
我可以跟奇斯去
Chase and I can go.
只有这样才公平
It's only fair.
公平最重要
Fairness is important.
你异常安静
You're awfully quiet.
不好意思  我呆在杀人犯旁边
Sorry. That's just how I get around people
一般就会这样
who have recently killed a man.
事情不是
It wasn't...
这一年我过得很辛苦
You know, I've had a pretty rough year.
你觉得我们能不能
Do you think maybe we could just
把这事先放一放
give this whole thing a rest?
你杀了人
You killed a man.
但你以滥开处方为由辩护
But you pled out to drugs.
在嗑药的情况下肇事逃逸
Hit-and-run under the influence.
刚才被你踢中要害的人
Guy you kneed in the groin
就是你当时的约会对象
was your date
他向警察举报了你
who dropped a dime on you.
我请求你别问了
I'm asking you to let it go.
我也希望我是不喜欢
And I really wish I was the kind of person
刨根问底的那种人
who could do that.
露比  对吧
Ruby, right?
没错
Yeah.
你觉得这医院怎么样
Hey, how are you liking PPTH?
很好  每个人都很友好
It's great. Everyone's so friendly.
没错  尤其是陶博医生
Yeah. Especially Dr. Taub.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不是想让你难堪
I'm not gonna bust your chops.
我只是想知道一件事
I just want to know one thing.
他是怎么成功把你约出去的
How did he get you to go out with him?
怎么了  是不是有什么
Why? Is--is there something--
不不  他  他人很好
No, no, no, no, he's--he's great.
我只是随便问问
I'm--you know, I'm just asking
因为...
because...
他...
Well, he's...
算了
You know what, never mind.
与我无关
It's none of my business.
祝你们今晚玩的开心
You guys have fun tonight.
我今晚不和他出去
I'm not seeing him tonight.
本来要的  但他变卦了
We had plans, but he canceled.
这东西没有燃油阀
This thing's got no fuel valve.
就是说没办法控制进油量
Means you can't regulate the input.
这是什么  烧烤点火器吗
And what is this? A barbecue lighter?
你的枪太逊了
Your gun sucks.
我们应该把这当作一次考古挖掘
We should treat this like an archaeological dig.
分好区域  挖掘  记录  分析
Grid the site, excavate, catalog, analyze.
你喜欢这里
You like it here.
你不觉得这很吸引人吗
You don't think this is fascinating?
你认为这里吸引人的想法
Not nearly as fascinating as the fact
更加吸引人
that you think it's fascinating.
但这人保留了所有
But this guy kept everything
他曾经接触过的东西
he ever came into contact with.
一部活的生活史
An interactive life history.
只是一堆乱扔的垃圾而已
It's an indiscriminate pile of rubbish.
大部分时候
Well, for the most part,
我们的生活也是如此
so are our lives.
没有检测到一氧化碳
There's no carbon monoxide.
否定了福曼的毒物暴露假设
A bit of a blow to Foreman's exposure hypothesis
也否定了我想赶快离开的计划
and my plan to get out of here quickly.
或许我们不该只琢磨什么导致了他的症状
Maybe we don't just figure out the what,
也弄明白为什么
we figure out the why.
或许就可以
Then maybe...
从尺寸和未消化的种子推断
From the size and the undigested seeds,
我估计这是浣熊排泄的
I'm guessing this came from a raccoon.
如果你觉得是寇热
If you're thinking Q fever,
症状是符合的
it fits.
那为什么我们还在找啊
So why are you still looking?
你只找出了一种可能
Well, you only found one thing.
它完全符合啊
It fits perfectly.
没错  但这不意味着
Yeah, but that doesn't mean...
奇斯
Chase.
你们在他家查漏了点东西
You missed something at his place.
他妻子
His wife.
妮娜
Nina.
我不知道你去哪里了
I didn't know where you were.
对不起  我没法回家
I'm so sorry. I couldn't get home.
你还好吗
You okay?
我们认为你们都感染了寇热
We think you both have Q fever.
在厨房的碗橱里发现了浣熊的粪渣
Found raccoon feces in the kitchen cupboard.
我们会开始用多西环素治疗你
We're gonna start you on doxycycline.
你为什么不告诉我们你结婚了
Why wouldn't you tell us you're married?
越少人知道她
The fewer people who know about her,
事情就会越容易
the easier it is.
我什么时候能回家
When can I go back?
当她离开她的收藏物时她就会变得焦虑
She gets anxious when she's away from her things.
她才是那个囤积者  他只是住在那里
She's the hoarder. He just lives there.
是自愿的吗
On purpose?
她是我的妻子
She's my wife.
他们怎么能没有半英寸钻头呢
How do they not have 1/2-inch drill bits?
顺便说一句  哈罗德可能会和你调情
By the way, Harold's probably gonna hit on you.
所有我的东西  他都想要
Everything I have, he wants.
只要干脆地拒绝他就行了
Just turn him down flat.
-除非  -是啊
- Unless... - Yes.
咱别买东西了
Let's stop shopping.
我去把他上了然后让他退赛就好了
I'll just do him and get him to throw the contest.
我没想...
I'm not sugges...
你会这么做吗
Would you do that?
这个比赛是怎么评分的呢
How's this thing judged?
腾空时间  射程和准确度
Hang time, distance, and accuracy.
这个怎么样
Okay, how about this?
你在酒吧里遇到一个男人
You met a guy in a club,
你把他带回家  他嗑药过度死了
you brought him home, he O.D.'d,
而那个在家门口疼得打滚的男的
so the guy now writhing on his front porch
就是卖给你次品的毒贩子
was the dealer who sold you the faulty goods.
-每一项占的分都一样吗  -没错
- Categories weighted the same? - Yup.
别管准确度了  我们加倍射程
Screw accuracy. We're gonna double distance
和腾空时间  在总分上击败哈罗德
and hang time, beat Harold on points.
我们需要点强劲的力量
We need raw power.
肥料在哪里
Where's the fertilizer?
不择手段啊  凯辛斯基
By all means, Kaczynski.
你和陶博现在都共用电话了吗
You and taub sharing phones now?
他在和三楼那个红头发的女人约会
He's seeing the redhead on the third floor.
你不会是在说
Please tell me you're not talking
那个新来的有酒窝的护士吧
about the hot new cna with the dimples.
她承认了
She confirmed it.
不过她说今晚没有约会
What she didn't confirm was their date tonight.
他毁约了
He bailed on her.
如果他放她鸽子
If he's standing her up,
他一定找到了更好的
he must have something better going on.
比和22岁的女人上床更好的吗
Better than sex with a 22-year-old?
谁是阿蒂92啊
Who's Artie92?
大概是个21岁的
Presumably a 21-year-old.
不管是谁
Whoever it is,
八点的时候陶博要和她在我家见面
Taub's meeting 'em at my place at 8:00,
也就是我通常去健身房的时间
which is usually when I go to the gym.
看来你要缺席今晚的舞蹈课了
Guess you'll be missing spin class.
选手们  场地现在开放训练
Okay, contestants, the field is now open for practice.
你们有一个小时的时间  玩得开心
You've got one hour. Have fun.
SCH 80 PVC管的额定压强是1.52兆帕
Schedule 80 PVC is pressure rated for 220 psi,
燃油阀压力为2.07兆帕
fuel valve 300.
我们可以很轻易地加压到1.72
We can easily push it to 250,
让你的哈罗德小朋友屁滚尿流
have your friend Harold peeing in his pants.
靠
Damn.
淡定
Be cool.
哈罗德
Harold.
豪斯
House.
你看起来不错
You look good.
我喜欢你身上这件夹克
I like that jacket on you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你变胖了点
You filled out a little.
这个小妞是谁啊
Who's the babe?
她是踢你屁股的人
She's the boot in your ass.
你可听说过著名的俄罗斯物理学家
Perhaps you've heard a fame -- the Russian physicist
奥尔加·彼得罗维奇
Olga Petrovich?
奥尔加·彼得罗维奇已经七十二岁了
Olga Petrovich is 72 years old.
她的孙女
And her granddaughter
在喷气推进实验室工作
works at a little place called JPL.
我去年夏天就在那里实习
I did an internship there last summer.
她杀了一个人
She killed a man.
估计她的凶器肯定不是土豆枪
I'm guessing she didn't do it with a spud gun.
只是走火了
Just a bad combustion valve.
闭嘴吧
Shut up.
在我的沙发上
On my sofa.
你还记得我老婆吧
You remember my wife.
你好  艾瑞克
Hi, Eric.
你好  阿蒂92
Hey, Artie92.
但愿你喜欢吃大黄
I hope you like rhubarb.
我们来庆祝庆祝
We're celebrating.
我们要出大招了
We're going rogue.
把燃机阀取出
We rip out the combustion valve,
用圆盘代替
replace it with disks.
在足够大的压力下
With enough pressure,
就能打出最大的速度
it should blow out at maximum velocity.
把土豆变成土豆卫星
Turning the spud into spudnik.
我们用什么作圆盘
What do we use for disks?
给你个提示
Well, here's a hint.
我其实很讨厌吃大黄
I actually hate rhubarb.
锡盘[烤派的盘子是锡做的]
Pie tins.
你是个天才
You're a genius.
我是个医生
You know that I'm a doctor.
我对人体的兴趣纯粹是出自
Any interest I have in the human body
临床工作的需要
is purely clinical.
对我从来都不适用
Yeah, that line never works for me either.
那句话对你一直是适用的
That line always works for you.
你到底做什么了
So what did you do?
就不再猜了吗
No more guessing?
我得搞清楚
I need to know.
我可以打几个电话
I can make some phone calls,
看能否提前你的医委会听证
see if we can speed up your medical board hearing.
与此同时
In the meantime,
没人能阻止我招一个助手
no one could stop me from hiring an assistant.
今早你说对了
You were right this morning.
我在咖啡店遇到了个男的
I met a guy at a coffee shop,
我们去我家鬼混
we went back to my place,
他吸毒过量了
and he O.D.'d.
妈的
Damn.
我本来可以省下一个工作职位的
I could have saved myself a job offer.
我俩都装不知道
We both acted like idiots.
结果我被判了服刑
And I ended up doing time.
可能他被判的更久
Guess he did more.
我们刚搬进去的时候
When we first moved into the house,
一直都有人来看望我们
we had people over all the time.
后来她开始收集东西
Then she started collecting things.
我以为是她的兴趣
I figured it was a hobby.
把堆品做成了艺术品
Piles turned into art projects,
艺术品又变成了你们所看到的样子
and art projects turned into what you saw.
那你为什么还留在那里呢
So why do you stay?
对其他人来说  这个世界到处是垃圾
To everyone else, the world is full of junk--
无意义的  丑陋的  破烂的垃圾
meaningless, ugly, broken things.
但是在妮娜看来
But to Nina,
每一种形状
every shape,
每一种的颜色  纹理  味道
every color, texture, smell,
都讲述了一个故事
they all tell a story.
都是值得珍视的东西
They're all worth treasuring.
我并不奢望别人也能理解她的想法
I wouldn't wish what she has on anyone,
但时不时的我瞥一眼
but every now and then I get a glimpse
她所看到的世界...
of what she sees, and...
我就懂了
it helps.
肺部的杂音正在减轻
Your lungs are clearing up nicely.
呼吸频率正常  体温正常
Respiratory rate's normal. Temp's normal.
看来你很快会好起来
Looks like you're gonna be fine.
她还好吗
She okay?
她的心脏出问题了
Something's wrong with her heart.
丈夫好转了  妻子却恶化了
The husband is fine. The wife is worse.
她心脏病发作了
She had a heart attack.
她的心脏病发作可能是
Her heart attack could be
并发症导致的
from a complication.
寇热可能会引起充血性心力衰竭
Q fever would cause congestive heart failure,
但不会引起心肌梗塞
not myocardial infarction.
那是说她不单患了寇热还有其它
So she had Q fever and something else
引起心脏病的原因吗
that causes heart attack?
还有囤积癖
And the hoarding.
现在他妻子才是病人
Now that the wife is the only patient,
我们需重新考虑囤积癖
hoard is back on the board.
或者我们对寇热的诊断是错的
Or we were wrong about Q fever.
我可不认为只是个巧合
I don't buy it's just a coincidence.
当然不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
未知病因导致了囤积癖
Diagnosis X caused the hoarding,
浣熊去她家度春假时
which caused the Q fever when the raccoons came
囤积癖又导致了寇热
to spend spring break at her house.
此刻我们的任务是解出未知病因
Now all we have to do is solve for X.
我记得有人说
I remember somebody saying that
囤积癖可能是种病症
hoarding could be a symptom.
我们得给她做个核磁共振
We should do an MRI.
硫化氢
Hydrogen sulfide.
鸡蛋和腐败的食物中会散发出硫化氢
It's given off by eggs and rotting food.
长期暴露在硫化氢中会造成肺部疾病
Long-term exposure could cause the pulmonary issues,
-头疼...  -甚至心脏病
- headaches... - Even the heart attack.
硫化氢也是种血管舒张剂
Hydrogen sulfide is also a vasodilator.
而我杰出的小组却从没检测过硫化氢
Which my crack team never tested the place for.
当然  还有半个杰出小组
Of course, half my crack team
从未检测过他们家是否有人
never tested the place for people.
就是说我们得回去
So we should go back,
验证下
check it out.
假设我们诊断准确开始治疗会更安全
Might be safer to just assume we're right and start treatment.
于上帝同行吧
Go with God.
记得带空气清新剂
And some air freshener.
可能陶博是对的
You know, maybe Taub is right,
所以我要留这里帮他做核磁共振
so I'm gonna stay here with him and help him with the MRI.
伙计们  擦亮你们的土豆
Shine up your spuds, folks.
几分钟之后  我们就将开始
We're gonna start shooting for hang time
腾空时间比赛
in just a few minutes.
吹的是东南风
The wind's coming from the southeast.
你得把准心往左调五度
You have to aim five degrees to the left.
我们能打破十四秒记录  我有感觉
We're gonna break 14 seconds. I can feel it.
我十岁还十一岁的时候
When I was 10 or 11,
我爸常带我们去集市上
my dad used to take us to this county fair.
有那么个小孩
And there was this kid...
什么
What?
我们是谁
Who's "us"?
我妈妈和我
My mom and me.
你那位当时已是亨廷顿病晚期的妈妈吗
Your mom who had advanced stage huntington's.
你有个兄弟或姊妹  却从未提及
You have a sibling that you've never mentioned.
怎么现在突然说漏嘴
Why did you slip up now?
不是每个细节都有说道
Not everything means something.
马上就到我们了
We're gonna be up soon.
我得检查下压力
I want to check the pressure.
你不会半夜醒来
You don't wake up in the middle of the night
为陌生死者流泪
to cry over a dead stranger.
你不会坦白杀了人
You don't confess to killing a man
却又隐瞒细节
and then hide the details.
除非比起犯罪事实  细节更能揭露
Unless the details reveal more about you
有关你的信息
than the crime itself.
你被轻判为滥用药物
You pled down to drugs.
你患有可怕的遗传病
You've got a horrible genetic disease
还突然说漏嘴有手足
and a sibling who's suddenly on your mind.
你给你哥做了安乐死
You euthanized your brother.
你之前找的那家伙是医生
And that guy back at the house was the doctor
他不愿帮你隐瞒
who wouldn't help you cover it up.
我之前找的那家伙
The guy back at the house
是我牢友的男友
is my cellmate's boyfriend.
她坐牢期间  他对她不忠
He cheated on her when she was inside.
但其余的我都说对了
But I was right about everything else.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你生气了
You're mad.
没有
No.
事实上  我对你刮目相看
Actually, I'm impressed.
一边糊弄22岁的靓妹
Messing around on a 22-year-old hottie
一边跟老婆搞到我的沙发上
with your wife on my sofa.
你是脑袋糨糊了吧
You're a full-throttle head case.
选沙发算帮你忙了
I was doing you a solid with the sofa.
瑞秋还想躺你床上做呢
Rachel wanted to do it in your bed.
那可是记忆海绵床垫
You've got the memory foam top.
挑明了说
Let's make this really simple:
我不希望你在我的家具上面做
If I own it, I don't want you doing it on it.
那你可能不会再想要厨房的桌子了
You might want to get rid of your kitchen table.
听着  我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry,
-不过还挺值的  -是啊  我想也是
- but it was worth it. - Yeah, I bet.
你能同时在肉体上精神上折腾她
You get to mess with her physically and emotionally.
我仍关心她
I still care about her.
显然不足以放手给她新生活
Not enough to let her move on with her life.
我们讨论你那些破事的同时
While we're talking about your bad ideas,
核磁共振没有异常
MRI's clean.
她肯定有发生过
There has to be some kind
心理剧变
of inciting psychological incident.
太适合你了
This is perfect for you.
不用进行实际接触
You get all the human interaction you crave
就能得到你渴望的与人交互感
without any actual human interaction.
她曾是拉拉队长  厉害
She was a cheerleader. Huh.
知道吗  当你着迷于他人毫无兴趣的事
You know when you're interested in something and nobody else is,
礼貌做法  就是自己一边玩儿去
the polite thing is to keep it to yourself.
受人欢迎  长得水灵  社交达人
Popular, beautiful, gregarious.
硫化氢含量十亿分之二
Hydrogen sulfide's about two parts per billion.
放个屁的含量
The size of a healthy fart.
七月见[再也不来了]
I'll be back for you in July.
迈克尔·杰克逊于09年6月底去世
此处影射其无法兑现的约定"七月见"
他没法自我了结
He couldn't do it himself.
他  病情恶化得太快
He was--the disease had progressed too far.
他全身颤搐
He was flailing.
完全失去控制
He didn't have any control over his own body.
长时间意识不清
He pretty much lost control of his mind too,
但
but...
隔三岔五  还能有
every once in a while, he would have a few seconds
片刻清醒
of lucidity.
他向我求助  他说
He turned to me, and he said,
"是时候了"
"It's time."
我在静脉注射药物里动了手脚
I hooked up the I.V.
我戴了手套  我知道他们会根据药物找到我
I used gloves. I knew they'd get me on the drugs,
但他们没法证明是谁推的活塞
but they couldn't prove who pushed the plunger.
一针下去
I put in the needle,
他就
and he just...
变得好安静
got quiet.
一切都结束了
And it was over.
就剩我独自一人
And I was alone.
某天  我也会落到那般田地
And one day, I will be that sick,
待到那时  却没有人
and there will be no one there
会送我一程
when it's time.
我没指望要博你同情
I didn't expect compassion from you.
我该得到失去亲人的哀悼之词
I would have taken commiseration.
该死的  我该得到弑兄的厌恶之词
Hell, I would have taken revulsion,
带有个人情绪的任何表示都好
any emotional engagement at all.
难怪卡迪会跟你分手
It's no wonder Cuddy broke up with you.
各位  查德·洛克比刚获得
Folks, Chad Lockerbie just won
辣豆汤烹饪大赛冠军
first place in the chili cook-off.
恭喜你  查德
Congratulations, Chad.
可可粉调味真是出奇制胜
That cocoa powder really did it.
在斯克内克塔迪的沃土上被甩
Dumped in a field in Schenectady.
哎呦
Ouch.
介意我补上吗
You mind if I make a move?
我自知配不上她
I know she's out of my league,
可她在马铃薯加农炮大赛上
but she's at a spud gun contest
陪着千年老二
with the soon-to-be five-time runner-up,
不免情难以堪  期许冠军臂弯吧
so she's probably got some self-esteem issues.
你不会开炮的
You wouldn't.
-怎样  -口头警告
- So? - Warning.
只给你口头警告吗
They gave you a warning?
事实上我们的老弟哈罗德
Well, it turns out our friend Harold
在昨夜土豆泥宴交谊会上
felt up the sheriff's daughter
调戏警长千金
last night at the potato mash mixer,
所以警长难以秉公执法
so sheriff's feeling kind of ambivalent.
你总能全身而退  是吧
You always get your way, don't you?
也不总是
Not always.
今天本该是我跟卡迪的一周年纪念日
Today would have been our one-year anniversary.
总该好好庆祝才是
Which is an incredibly arbitrary thing to celebrate.
想要知根知底
If you want to get to the bottom of something,
就得找到根源才行
you literally have to dig down to the bottom.
按地质年代讲
So stratigraphically,
就我发现最老的收集物出现在卧室
the oldest stuff I found was in the bedroom.
卧室里最旧的家什是衣柜
And the oldest stuff in the bedroom was in the closet.
在衣柜的最下面
And at the bottom of the closet...
跟我说说这个
Tell me about this.
发现新症状
We have a new symptom.
不孕
Infertility.
他们想要孩子  可是一直怀不上
They wanted kids but couldn't have them.
她就开始收集东西填补空虚
She started collecting things to fill the void.
应该做个全方位荷尔蒙血液测定
We should run a full hormone blood panel.
小侦探哈里特[儿童读物]
Hey, Harriet the Spy,
先别着急忙活
before you get too full of yourself,
复习一下生物基础课
you might want to go back to bio 101.
巧妇难为无米之炊
It takes two to not-tango.
丈夫的精子可能有问题
Hubby could be shooting blanks.
所以这可能是助我们救她一命的新症状
So either it's a new symptom that will help us save her life
也可能是在枉费时间
or it's a complete waste of time.
查查是哪个的问题  培根还是蛋[他还是她]
Figure out which is fried, the bacon or the eggs.
我去开始荷尔蒙检测
I'll start the hormone workup.
还有另一种可能
There's another option.
豪斯  谁在说话
House, who's that?
电台
Radio.
听起来很像十三
Sounded a lot like thirteen.
模仿十三的乐队出了新歌
It's a thirteen tribute band with their new song,
《我的推测比马斯特斯好》
"I've got a better theory than Masters."
她说他们没有过孩子
She said they never had kids.
我的天哪  你到哪里去了
Oh, my God. Where the hell have you been?
我想我们都还有更要紧的事情
I think we've all got something a little more important
-需要关心  -这很要紧
- to worry about than... - No, we don't.
她杳无音信整整一年了
She's been missing for a year.
你们等她周一上班的时候再问好了
You can ask her all about it when she comes in on Monday.
周一
Monday?
下周一
This Monday?
我可以说话了吗
Can I talk?
她说他们没有过孩子
She said they never had kids,
你们就直接认定为不孕
and you all jumped to infertility.
忽略了另一种可能
You never considered the other option.
哈十三又回来啦
And the bitch is back.
我们认为你患有埃莱尔-当洛综合症
We think you have Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome.
与你的症状完全相符
It would explain the symptoms.
此病还会导致流产
It also causes miscarriages.
你有过这样的经历吗
Is that something you think you might have?
你怀上过
Were you pregnant?
三次
Three times.
多次流产致使她囤积成癖
The miscarriages triggered the hoarding.
最终导致你也生病
Hoarding eventually made you sick too.
你们能治好她吗
Can you cure her?
出现的身体症状可以治疗
We can treat the physical symptoms
改善她的生活
as they arise, make her life a lot better,
但是囤积癖
but the hoarding,
不在我们的治疗范围内
we're the wrong kind of doctors.
你骗了我
You lied to me?
整整九年
For nine years?
我太害怕会失去你
I was so afraid of losing you.
我做了什么让你怕成这样
What have I ever done to make you afraid of that?
我得出去透口气
I need to get some air.
是我一直太自私
I've been selfish.
我应该让你
I need to let you
过自己的生活
move on.
我想我们不该再见面了
I think we should stop seeing each other.
不
No.
我只是想给你一个
Um, I just want you to be able to...
你上一次跟我玩绅士
The last time you got all noble on me,
闹得我们离婚连餐具都分了
we ended up dividing our dishes.
这一次  我来做决定
This time, I want to make the decision.
我们这样你不觉得别扭吗
You don't feel weird about this?
我当然觉得别扭
Of course I feel weird about this.
而且混乱困惑
It's confusing and messy
肮脏龌龊
and dirty.
愚蠢
Dumb.
可你看看我们俩  一辈子都怕犯错
But we spent our whole lives trying to do everything right,
-结果非常失败  -也没那么差啦
- and it sucked. - It wasn't all bad.
真的很失败  克里斯
It sucked, Chris.
可现在
And this,
不论这算什么
whatever it is,
都很好玩
It's fun.
那我不是在占你便宜吧
So I'm not taking advantage of you?
不好玩了
The fun is fading.
知道吗
You know...
我们俩真是无可救药了
There's something seriously wrong with us.
我知道
I know.
家啊甜蜜的家
Home, sweet home.
你欠我87块汽油钱
You owe me 87 bucks for gas.
我来杀你
I'll kill you.
等时候到了  如果你要我动手的话
When the time comes, if you want me to.
你愿意的话我现在就动手
I'll do it now if you like.
我后备箱应该有根棒球棒
I think I've got a baseball bat in the back.
周一见
I'll see you Monday.